<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Huw Fulcher</title>
    <link>https://huwfulcher.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Huw Fulcher</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://huwfulcher.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Simplifying your life shouldn’t cause overwhelm</title>
      <link>https://huwfulcher.com/blog/2023-03-14-simplifying-your-life-shouldnt-lead-to-overwhelm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://huwfulcher.com/blog/2023-03-14-simplifying-your-life-shouldnt-lead-to-overwhelm/</guid>
      <description>A question I ask often and try and act on is “How can I simplify my life to the things I want without feeling overwhelmed?”
The fact I get overwhelmed in simplifying my life is a tell that I’m not actually simplifying my life at all.
If the act of simplifying is causing overwhelm then I suspect it’s actually about putting more concerted effort on doing certain things more rather than living them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A chance encounter</title>
      <link>https://huwfulcher.com/blog/2023-01-29-a-chance-encounter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://huwfulcher.com/blog/2023-01-29-a-chance-encounter/</guid>
      <description>Matthew 13:31-32 (ESV)
[31] He put another parable before them, saying, “The kingdom of heaven is like a grain of mustard seed that a man took and sowed in his field. [32] It is the smallest of all seeds, but when it has grown it is larger than all the garden plants and becomes a tree, so that the birds of the air come and make nests in its branches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A kinder way to reach our goals</title>
      <link>https://huwfulcher.com/blog/2023-01-10-a-kinder-way-to-reach-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://huwfulcher.com/blog/2023-01-10-a-kinder-way-to-reach-goals/</guid>
      <description>The best intentions It&amp;rsquo;s 2023, goals, aspirations and habits are being scribbled down by people round the world. All of this is being framed by a thought, &amp;ldquo;what should I be doing better this year?&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty standard thought that everyone has and I&amp;rsquo;m not saying that it&amp;rsquo;s bad but that it might hamstring us more than we think.
For me, the pressure to do things better has had a two fold effect on my mental health and also my ability to get things done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I wish brand loyalty was more of a thing</title>
      <link>https://huwfulcher.com/blog/2023-01-07-i-kind-of-wish-brand-loyalty-was-more-of-a-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://huwfulcher.com/blog/2023-01-07-i-kind-of-wish-brand-loyalty-was-more-of-a-thing/</guid>
      <description>In a previous job I worked for an agency who were big on helping clients to develop brand loyalty. Understandably, the main driver for brand loyalty for businesses most of the time is a bigger market share and more profit, but from a customer side I&amp;rsquo;ve been mulling over how brand loyalty can actually enrich our lives as well.
A symbol of aspiration Recently, my wife and I stayed at the Celtic Manor for a night to have a babymoon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capturing information by actionability not category</title>
      <link>https://huwfulcher.com/blog/2023-01-05-capturing-information-by-actionability-not-category/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://huwfulcher.com/blog/2023-01-05-capturing-information-by-actionability-not-category/</guid>
      <description>Initially this post was going to a way to vent about Knowledge Bases/Second Brains and how they encourage &amp;ldquo;information gluttony&amp;rdquo; rather than mindful consumption and collection.
Doing some due diligence on the topic first I started watching Ali Abdaal&amp;rsquo;s video on building a second brain and found that actually it may be better than I thought.
Rather than waste the opportunity to put a post out I&amp;rsquo;m repurposing this article to explore a particular idea expressed in the video and by Tiago Forte, the author behind &amp;ldquo;Building a Second Brain&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a chain isn&#39;t as important as making an effort</title>
      <link>https://huwfulcher.com/blog/2023-01-03-making-a-chain-isnt-as-important-as-making-an-effort/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://huwfulcher.com/blog/2023-01-03-making-a-chain-isnt-as-important-as-making-an-effort/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s common knowledge for those with new year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions that keeping track of your new habits with streaks (or chains) is touted as a way to achieve them. For the past few years I&amp;rsquo;ve sought to take the same approach and crack out the habit tracker and make it a goal to keep the streaks running as long as possible. Unfortunately they always fizzle out far too quickly.
I don&amp;rsquo;t think that habit tracking in and of itself is bad but the mindset we can build around it can be a hinderance rather than a help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to integrate TinaCMS with Jekyll</title>
      <link>https://huwfulcher.com/blog/2022-11-10-how-to-integrate-tinacms-with-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://huwfulcher.com/blog/2022-11-10-how-to-integrate-tinacms-with-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Introduction TinaCMS, the successor to Forestry has just gone to v1.0, bringing a stable, open-source, git based CMS to static sites. I&amp;rsquo;ve just started using TinaCMS with my site and I&amp;rsquo;m actually writing this post using it!
While there is some documentation on adding TinaCMS to a non-NextJS site there are few extra steps that are needed to get it working nicely with Jekyll.
1. Install TinaCMS npx @tinacms/cli@latest init Note: Docs as of (10/11/2022) specify a &amp;ndash;static flag, this is removed and won&amp;rsquo;t work Choose whatever package manager is preferable Choose Other when asked for a framework (Optional) Use Typescript, it is recommended When asked where public assets are stored specify the top level with /.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
